A Journey around Uluru
In the center of Australia lies Uluru,
the great Swayambhu of Shri Ganesha.
At this sacred place, Uluru is accompanied by Atila and Kata Tjuta,
two other great geological formations.
Atila, 200 million years older than Uluru,
is a monolith shaped like a bandhan,
and rises 300 m above the plain, 100 km east of Uluru.
According to the pre-ancestral stories,
it is a place created for man out of ice.
So, the home of the "ice people."
It is the place of Shri Sadashiva...
Kata Tjuta, a group of enormous stone domes,
is located 27 km west of Uluru.
Its highest peak reaches 545 m above the plain.
This traditionally sacred place is the setting
of the creation stories of the Great Serpent.
It is the dwelling of the female ancestors...
Uluru, the second largest monolith in the world,
rises 318 m above the plain,
is 8 km in circumference,
and extends 2.5 km into the ground.
At dawn on August 14, 2005, we made our pilgrimage
by walking around its base in a clockwise direction.
Uluru is the site of important Aboriginal ceremonies
that we did not photograph,
in accordance with the wishes of its traditional owners.
To the traditional owners of this land,
the Anangu,
their land was returned in 1985
by the Australian government.
Please, do not climb Uluru.
It is a truly important, sacred place that you are climbing.
You should not. It is not something to be done."
Kunmanara, Traditional Owner.
Shri Ganesha, may I be worthy of Your attention.
Please make me innocent, so that I may be worthy of Your attention.
Shri Mataji, You who are Shri Ganesha,
please grant me wisdom and discernment."
"Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi